ILGWU Graphics 5780 G
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Graphics
1944-1982
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780 G
6.61 cubic feet
4.9 linear ft.
Graphics, cameraless animation.
The collection contains assorted publications, as well as graphics, advertisments and posters created by or used by the ILGWU.
7461797
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, October 01, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/109: ILGWU Broadside Collection
Clothing workers -- Labor unions; Textile workers -- Labor unions
7461797
- Der Arbeter Kamf (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Calling All Shops - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dress Bulletin - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dos Freis Wort: 1926-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The ILG'er: v.2:no.7 (1946:Aug/Sept); v.14:no.3 (1960:Summer), 1946-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- In Kampf: v.1:no.3 (1926:Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Ladies' Garment Cutter: 1913-1917 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Ladies' Garment Worker: v.5:no.2 (1953:Dec.); v.6:no.1 (1954:July), 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Local 22 Dressmaker - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Local 23-25 News - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Local 99 News - 1954-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Local 105 Reports - 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Monatlakher Idisher Bulletin - 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Needle Worker - 1924-1933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The New Post - 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Nineteen Twenty-Three - v.1:no.1 (1927) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Pennsylvania Labor Record - v.11:no.33 (1943:Dec.) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Progressive Dressmaker - 1934-1935, 1935-1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Der Progresiver Kapn in Millinery Arbeter - 1927 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- The Progressive Unionist - v.1:no.1-4 (1936) (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Sew-Sew News - v.1:no.7 (1940:May); v.1:no.8 (1940:Oct.) (Box 1, Folder 22)
- The Shipping Clerk - v.5:no.2 (1957:June) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Shop News - no.6,7,9,20,21 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Treyo Yanyon Zenter - v.1:no.1-2 (1930) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- The Union Dressmaker - v.1:no.1-3 (1934) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Union Vanguard - 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- United Dressmaker - v.1:no.1 (1935) (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Unzer Wort - 1926-1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Workers Age - 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Advertisement boards (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Assorted advertisement boards and advertisement ideas
- Advertisement boards (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Advertisement boards (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Bus advertisements - 10 rolled and 2 broadsides (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Graphics (Box 12, Folder 1)
  Writing style examples; Advertising ideas; News paper article examples; copies of news paper articles; templates for advertising
- Joao Paulo - ILG Cartoons (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Broadsides; Winter scene of White House (1986) [appears to be a copy of a watercolor, sent out as a Christmas card from President Jimmy Carter] (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Art work - Union Label (Josh Schwartz); Unlabeled graphics; ILGWU Cartoons and The Institution Today (Box 13, Folder 3)
- ILGWU Graphics - some items were orig. box 5 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Graphics - some items were orig. box 6 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Graphics (Box 16, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Graphics (Box 17, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Graphics (Box 18, Folder 1)
- ILGWU Graphics (Box 19, Folder 1)
- "If you don't come in on Sunday, don't come in on Monday" (broadside) and a photo of 5 women sewing (32"x41") (Box 20, Folder 1)
- A Unique Television treat full length feature film "With These Hands" starring Sam Levene (poster/broadside) (Box 21, Folder 1)
- ILGWU 'Fight Nazism and Fascism' poster (Mitchell Loeb, 1934) (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Bus advertisements 12 rolled (Box 23, Folder 1)
- The Garment Jungle Promotional Posters using screenshots from the movie, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  8 small posters
- With These Hands Promotional Poster, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  advertising the showing of "With These Hands" on Channel 6, Saturday, February 14, 1950 at 3:00 p.m.
- Organizing at the North Pole Poster (Box 24, Folder 3)
  Labor themed version of Twas the Night Before Christmas
- Victory Poster for Local 23-25, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  Poster celebrating winning union contracts after the rallies in Chinatown on June 24, 1982 and July 15, 1982; includes Chinese
- Enlarged and Reproduced pages from the "Forward", 1950 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  5 pages enlarged from the Art Section of "Forward" for May 21, 1950. Imagery and accompanying text include subjects of: Unity House, Buildings of the ILGWU (Health Centers, Office Buildings, and Radio Stations), World War II relief and aid, With These Han
- 70 Year Anniversary Advertisement, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  Copy of advertisement that ran in newspapers across the country celebrating 70 years of progress of the ILGWU
- ILGWU Campaign Committee for Roosevelt-Truman, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  "We Vote for Health-Home-Happiness, We Vote for Roosevelt-Truman" Poster
- ILGWU Campaign Committee for Roosevelt and Truman, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  "Don't Gamble With Your Future. Give to Save your Job-Your Family-Your Union-Your Future--Give to the ILGWU Campaign Committee for Roosevelt and Truman